### **KEVIN LEWIS**

+447496836652 ~ kvnalws.io ~ a\_phzn

## SUMMARY

\_\_\_\_\_\_

An experienced developer advocate, educator, and technical events coordinator. I help developers understand complex concepts so they can apply them to their projects and business cases. I enjoy working in teams where there is mutual support, whilst also being able to take initiative and work independently on projects. I am action-driven and enjoy both strategy-level planning and getting my hands dirty.

#### KEY COMPETENCIES

\_\_\_\_\_\_

#### Educational Content

Experienced in creating and maintaining content for developers including code demos, blog posts, videos, workshops, webinars and livestreams.

### Software Development

Skills include HTML, CSS & JavaScript, Vue.js, Node.js, Serverless, Static Site Generators, Git, working with Databases and REST APIs incl Communication and Video APIs. Light knowledge of Python, C++ and Java. Experience using several low and no-code platforms.

### Core Skills

I pride myself on being communicative, helpful and empathetic. I am comfortable asking for help when I need it and in supporting others where I can. I am flexible and can confidently self-prioritize my work to meet deadlines and milestones.

# WORK HISTORY

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# Developer Advocate, Vonage (Nexmo)

[2020 - Present]

- \* Created blog posts, videos, live streams, workshops, and a learn-to-code course.
- \* Designed a framework for creating lesson plans and five-minute demos.
- \* Built a developer-engagement tool for the Vonage Video API.
- \* Supported developers through troubleshooting and helping them use the APIs.
- \* Established consistent and automated tracking of community health and engagement data.

# Lead Organizer, You Got This Conferences

[2019 - Present]

- \* Established a soft skills conference series with a focus on inclusion.
- \* Identified talks, workshops, and sponsors that aid the growth of soft skills.
- \* Oversee four event teams running events in the UK, USA, Poland, and Germany.

### **Director**, Underland

[2017 - 2020]

- \* Created and delivered single and multi-day technical training courses.
- \* Released and maintained multiple production-ready software development projects.
- \* Organized developer events incl hackathons, conferences and meetups on behalf of clients.

## Developer & Technical Writer, Freelance

[2015 - 2017]

\* Various freelance technical writing and software development projects.

# Developer Community Manager, Digiotology

[2015 - 2016]

- \* Built an expert community from scratch, totalling over 150 members.
- \* Managed enterprise hackathons with internal and external stakeholders.
- \* Provided opportunities to community members based on mutual benefit.

## Developer Advocate Engineer, Rewired State

[2014 - 2015]

- \* Managed a UK-wide and online community of developers.
- \* Managed and mentored a community of young developers.
- \* Ran corporate hackathons bringing together our community members and clients.
- \* Created, launched and managed a developer champion programme.
- \* Established automations to enable greater team efficiency.

#### **EDUCATION**

BSc Creative Computing. First-Class Honors. University of London. 2016-2019.

#### PERSONAL INTERESTS

\_\_\_\_\_

I am a huge fan of getting together with friends, putting phones away and spending an evening with a selection of tabletop board and card games (the ones that end friendships are my favorite). I'm the official talent manager for my Jack Russell Moobean, and enjoy singing karaoke (badly) to my 6 month-old Sage.